They came to Earth to feed on human flesh!
The Deadly Spawn is a horror, science fiction film directed by Douglas McKeown.
When a meteorite touches down in the New Jersey woods carrying a monstrous alien slug, it’s up to
four teens to stop it before it’s terrifying brood consumes all life on Earth!
Charles, played by Charles George Hildebrandt.
Pete, played by Tom DeFranco.
Frankie, played by Richard Lee Porter.
Ellen, played by Jean Tafler.
Kathy, played by Karen Tighe.
Sam, played by James Brewster.
The Deadly Spawn is a 1983 American science fiction horror film written
and directed by Douglas McKeown, and produced by Ted A.
The film's plot centers on a meteor that lands on Earth, which unleashes a
carnivorous alien that finds refuge in the basement of a house.
As it grows larger, a young monster movie fan named Charles (Charles George Hildebrant)
and group of others try to survive against the creature and its offspring.
The Deadly Spawn was shot in New Jersey on 16 mm film.
The house in which the majority of the film takes place belonged to illustrator Tim
Hildebrandt, who also served as an executive producer on the film.
John Dods served as associate producer and special effects director; the
effects work involved wire-controlled rubber puppets.
Upon its release, in some territories, the film's title was changed to Return of the Aliens: The Deadly Spawn or The Return
of the Alien's Deadly Spawn in an attempt to capitalize on the worldwide success of the 1979 film Alien.
The film explores themes of monster, camping, alien, alien invasion, parasite.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.